# **CHRIS ARSENAULT**

**♀** Toronto Ontario

O chrisstanarsenault

## **EDUCATION**

# **SUMMARY**

Lighthouse Labs Oct. 2018 to Jan. 2019
Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

A full stack developer, with a passion for all things front-end. What I may lack in initial development experience, I make up for in an unwavering drive, dedication and desire to learn more, and to continue to grow my knowledge and skills. Also, with my many years of working in the hospitality district, I have substantial experience of working as a team, as well as team building. I am hoping to bring my eager attitude and past team experience into an innovative environment.

## **PROJECTS**

#### DRAWANGO

A drawing/guessing party game built to help learn to work further with React and Canvas in a realtime drawing environment. TechStacks: React, CSS/SASS, Express, NodeJS, Websockets

#### JUNGLE APP

An e-commerce Rails app built for learning Rails TechStacks: Ruby, Rails, Bootstrap, CSS/SASS, PG, Active Record

#### **CHATTY APP**

Simple single page chat app built with React and Websockets TechStacks: React. CSS/SASS. Express. NodeJS. JS. Websockets

#### **HOOKEAI POKE**

A food ordering and pickup service for the fictitious restaurant 'Hookeai Pookeai'
TechStacks: HTML, CSS/SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Express, NodeJS, EJS, PostSQL, Knex, AJAX, Twilio

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Ruby

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES, ENVIRONMENTS: NodeJS, React, AJAX, Express, Knex, JQuery, Bootstrap, Rails, Ruby, Websockets/Socket.io, Vue DATABASES, SYSTEMS, CMS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Git, WordPress

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### 416 MEDIA

WordPress Developer (freelance)

Toronto, Ontario Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2019

- helped with data entry work, moving information from old client site to new updated client site
- added some basic html tables to help organize some of the information
- helped with some custom css work to to fix with some of the formatting and look
- helped connect GoogleMap API and billing to new account

#### WORLD LEGAL SUMMIT

WordPress Developer

Toronto, ON Mar. 2019 to Sept. 2019

- general maintenance of the pre-existing website
- adjusting layouts as per client's needs
- maintaining and cleaning out plugins to help increase speed and search optimization. Brought PageSpeed score from initial 35% to 74%.
- implementing any new requested features or software needs such as:
  - live streaming capabilities for each host location
- set up Zendesk and customizing a custom theme for a knowledge base and community section
- integrated a method to connect the Mailchimp account with separate GoogleSheet sheets to collect
- signup information for each host, when interested parties requested an invite to their cities Summit.

- worked directly with each city host (approx 30-40) clients to add new updates and revisions to their individual event page (adding logos, documents, location details, speaker information, etc)

#### TORONTO LAWN TENNIS CLUB

Member Services Supervisor

Toronto, Ontario 2013 to 2018

- booking tennis/squash courts for members
- giving tours to new perspective members
- answering all inquiries
- being knowledgeable and up-to-date on all club related news and events
- training all new front desk staff
- helping out with any requests from other departments

### **AWARDS**

#### Toronto Lawn Tennis Club EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR

- I received this award for my dedication, focus, and willing to go above and beyond the call of duty

# VOLUNTEERING

# HEALTH & SAFETY COMMITTEE Co-Chair Toronto Lawn Tennis Club

- Helped the Chair run monthly committee meeting, and organize monthly club inspections

- Helped organize MDS binder and kept all MDS sheets up to date
- Attended classes to receive Health and Safety certification

2014 to 2018

2014